A Guide to the Christianburg Industrial Alumni Association, 1913,1966
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Christianburg Industrial Alumni Association, 1913,1966
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
1988-62
24 items
The Christianburg Industrial Alumni Association donated a collection of correspondence,photographs and artifacts. Included is an advanced English grammer textbook, which has a copyright date of 1913.Acc. # 1988-62
Christianburg Industrial Alumni Association
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Christianburg Industrial Alumni Association was formed in 1976. At this time a social organization was formed and they called themselves the "Christianburg Institute Alumni Association". The officers were David Hickman,President,Amanda DeHart,Vice President,Charles Johnson,Director of Affairs,Mattie P. Holmes,Recording Secretary,and Carrie Price,Treasurer.
Several committees were formed and the purpose of the organization was established. Through the succeeding years a number of meetings were held,a scholarship fund was established and in 1986 a commerative monument was erected on the site. Additional material about Christianburg may be found in the: John Banks Papers Acc.# 1984-34,The Amanda DeHart Papers Acc.# 1988-61, The Colson-Hill Family Papers Acc.# 1965-13, The VTA Papers Acc.#1969-14, and the VIA Papers ACC.# 1969-37 all may be found in the Virginia State University Special Collections Archives.
Scope and Content Information
These materials document the negative impact of school integration in Virginia. Throughout Virginia and south. Institutions that had been established,built and nurtured by the African American Community were by routine closed or down graded. The records of Christianburg and other schools for Frican American, thier accomplishments and failures help to document and define the reality of what was unequal and seperate.
Series Description
Series I. CIAA Letters Copies of the papers of Edgar A. Long 1966-1986
Series II. Photographs Class scenes 1948-1950 and 1962
Series III. Memorabilia Autograph book from the class of 1935
Series IV. Printed Programs: The Schaeffer Memorial Baptist Church
Series V. Scrapbook Titled the Second Collectable Book, Photographs, and News Clippings of school scenes and meetings of the Christianburg Alumni Association.
Series VI. Christianburg Artifacts Three dimentional items associated with the history of Christianburg Industrial Institute.
Contents List
- CIAA Letters
  - CIAA Letters 1966-1971 (Box-folder 1:1)
- Photographs
  - Photographs 1948,1962 (Box-folder 1:2)
- Memorabilia
  - Class Autograph Book 1935, 1:3 (Box-folder 1935)
- Printed
  - The Schaeffer Baptist Memorial Church Program (Box-folder 1:4)
- Scrapbook
  - Scrapbook (Box-folder 1:5)
- Christianburg Artifacts
  - News Journal 1959-1960 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - News Journal 1963 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Fourth Reunion Journal July 1986 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Yearbook 1942 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Yearbook 1943 (Folder 2:5)
  - Wide Windows- Book (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Complete Arithmetic-Math Book (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Modern English-Book (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Advance English Grammer-Book (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Four Christianburg Industrial Institute Pencils (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Mascot T-Shirt (Box-folder 2:11)
  - Christianburg Mascot Sweater (Box-folder 2:12)
  - Christianburg Mascot shorts (Box-folder 2:13)
  - Christianburg Mascot Sweatshirt (Box-folder 2:14)
  - Mascot flag and Button (Box-folder 2:15)
  - Pillow 1976 (Box-folder 2:16)
  - Seat Cushion 1976 (Box-folder 2:17)
  - String Art Trade Building (Box-folder 2:18)
  - Letter C (Box-folder 2:19)
  - Napkin/Envelope Holder (Box-folder 2:20)